

vijay.p.com | Linkedin | GitHub | FreeCodeCamp

19/14-B M C S R s t r e e t,Kumbakonam,Thanjavur,Tamilnadu. vijayponnaiyan93@gmail.com | Mobile: 8 7 6 0 6 4 8 6 8 0

Key Skill: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GitHub, JQuery, SASS, React.js...

## FRONT-END DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled front-end developer with over 1.7 years of experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, Bootstrap 5, and JQuery. I am experienced in creating responsive websites and have worked with well-known frameworks like Reactjs.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : JavaScript, ES6, HTML5, CSS3. **Frameworks** : Bootstrap 4 v 5 , jQuery , React.js .

**Databases** : MySQL, XAMPP, PHP.

**Dev Toolsl** : Visual Studio Code, Notepad++, GitHub.

Additional Skills: Nodejs, JSON, Typescript.

#### EXPERIENCE

## **Front-End Developer**

Pepy Technologies

July-2023 - Present

Coimbatore, Tamilnadu-641044

- In order to ensure the best possible user experience on all devices, Bootstrap is used in the development of custom websites. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and React.js.
- PHP Implementation By integrating PHP, interactive and dynamic features are created, which improves user engagement and functionality.XAMPP Usage: Proven ability to use XAMPP for local server setups to expedite development and guarantee smooth testing.

**Web Developer** Apr 2022 - June 2023

Freelance

Kumbakonam, Tamilnadu-612001

- \* Designed and developed dynamic and responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Bootstrap
- \* Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications

**UI / UX Designer** 2019 - 2020 Chennai

MacappStudio

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design intuitive user interfaces for web and mobile applications.
- \* Conducted user research, created wireframes, and developed interactive prototypes using tools like Adobe XD and Photo shop, Sketch.

## **EDUCATION**

# **B.E.- Aeronautical Engineering**

2014 - 2017

Mahendra Engineering College Namakkal, Tamilnadu-637503

#### **PROJECTS**

Project 1

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, and Git.

Source Code

VFX and Website Development: Make a special skills section highlighting your knowledge of website development technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, Bootstrap 5, jQuery. as well as VFX tools specify particular tools.

**Project 2** 

HTML5,CSS3,JavaScript,Bootstrap,jQuery,Git

Source Code

Extensive experience creating websites in the fast-paced environment of an IT tech and BPO organisation. We used these technologies to develop aesthetically pleasing, responsive websites that meet customer specifications.